So, let's talk about life.
我们来讨论人生
In life, there are two mistakes one can make.
一生中 人们都会犯两个错误
One is to try to kill Godzilla using a flyswatter.
一个是使用苍蝇拍消灭哥斯拉
The other one is to try to kill a fly using a bazooka.
另一个是使用火箭炮消灭苍蝇
What's the problem with trying to kill Godzilla with a flyswatter?
使用苍蝇拍消灭哥斯拉有什么问题呢？
That we're oversimplifying the problem.
因为我们过于简化问题
We're trying a solution that is too simple and won't do the job.
我们找到的解决方法过于简单 不会奏效
In machine learning, this is called underfitting.
在机器学习中 这叫欠拟合
And what's the problem with trying to kill a fly with a bazooka?
使用火箭炮消灭苍蝇有什么问题呢？
It's overly complicated and it will lead to bad solutions and
这样过于复杂 会导致解决方法很糟糕
extra complexity when we can use a much simpler solution instead.
和额外的复杂性 这时我们可以使用更简单的解决方法
In machine learning, this is called overfitting Let's look at how
在机器学习中 这叫过拟合
overfitting and underfitting can occur in a classification problem.
我们观察在分类问题中过拟合和欠拟合是如何出现的
Let's say we have the following data,
假如我们有下列数据
and we need to classify it.
需要进行分类
So what is the rule that will do the job here?
这里什么规则可以发挥效果呢？
Seems like an easy problem, right?
看起来是个很简单的问题 对不对
The ones in the right are dogs while the ones in the left are anything but dogs.
右侧是狗 而左侧是除了狗以外的东西
Now what if we use the following rule?
如果我们使用以下规则会怎么样？
We say that the ones in the right are
我们说右侧是动物
animals and the ones in the left are anything but animals.
而左侧是除了动物以外的东西
Well, that solution is not too good, right?
这个答案并不太好吧？
What is the problem?
问题是什么呢？
It's too simple. It doesn't even get the whole data set right.
这过于简单了 不能使整个数据集正确分类
See? It misclassified this cat over here since the cat is an animal.
明白了吗？ 它错误分类了这只猫 因为猫是动物
This is underfitting.
这是欠拟合
It's like trying to kill Godzilla with a flyswatter.
这就像是使用苍蝇拍消灭哥斯拉
Sometimes, we'll refer to it as error due to bias.
有时候我们会因为偏差把它当做误差
Now, what about the following rule?
现在下列规则会怎么样？
We'll say that the ones in the right are dogs that are yellow, orange,
我们说右侧的狗是黄色 橙色或灰色的
or grey, and the ones in the left are anything but dogs that are yellow, orange, or grey.
左侧是黄色 橙色或灰色狗以外的东西
Well, technically, this is correct as it classifies the data correctly.
从技术上来讲 如果对数据分类正确 这是正确的
There is a feeling that we went too specific since
因为只是说狗和狗以外的东西可以有效
just saying dogs and not dogs would have done the job.
感觉我们太过具体
But this problem is more conceptual, right?
不过这个问题更加概念化 对不对？
How can we see the problem here?
这里我们如何观察问题呢？
Well, one way to see this is by introducing a testing set.
其中一种观察方法是引入测试集
If our testing set is this dog over here,
如果我们的测试集是这里的狗
then we'd imagine that a good classifier would put it on the right with the other dogs.
我们可以想象 良好的分类器会把它放在右侧 与其他狗在一起
But this classifier will put it on the left since the dog is not yellow, orange, or grey.
不过因为狗不是黄色 橙色和灰色的 分类器把它放在左侧
So, the problem here, as we said,
正如我们所说 这里问题在于
is that the classifier is too specific.
分类器太过具体
It will fit the data well but it will fail to generalize.
它可以很好地拟合数据 却无法进行泛化
This is overfitting.
这是过拟合
It's like trying to kill a fly with a bazooka.
这就像是使用火箭炮消灭苍蝇
Sometimes, we'll refer to overfitting as error due to variance.
有时候我们会因为方差把过拟合当做误差
The way I like to picture underfitting and overfitting is when studying for an exam.
我绘制过拟合和欠拟合的方式是复习准备考试时
Underfitting, it's like not studying enough and failing.
欠拟合像是没有复习充分 考试失利
A good model is like studying well and doing well in the exam.
好的模型是学习充分 在考试中表现良好
Overfitting is like instead of studying,
过拟合像是没有学习
we memorize the entire textbook word by word.
而是逐字记忆整本教材
We may be able to regurgitate any questions in the textbook but we won't
我们也许能机械地回答教材上的问题
be able to generalize properly and answer the questions in the test.
却无法合理进行泛化 回答测试中的问题
But now, let's see how this would look like in neural networks.
不过现在我们来观察这在神经网络中的样子
So let's say this data where, again,
我们再来说这些数据
the blue points are labeled positive and the red points are labeled negative.
其中蓝点被标记为正 红点被标记为负
And here, we have the three little bears.
这里我们有三只小熊
In the middle, we have a good model which fits the data well.
中间是一个良好的模型 可以较好地拟合数据
On the left, we have a model that underfits since it's too simple.
左侧的模型欠拟合 因为它过于简单
It tries to fit the data with the line but the data is more complicated than that.
这个模型试图把数据拟合到这个线段上 但是数据过于复杂
And on the right, we have a model that overfits since it
右侧的模型过拟合 因为它
tries to fit the data with an overly complicated curve.
使用过于复杂的曲线拟合数据
Notice that the model in the right fits the data really well since it makes no mistakes,
注意右侧的模型确实可以很好地拟合术语 因为它没有错误
whereas the one in the middle makes this mistake over here.
而中间这个模型出现了错误
But we can see that the model in the middle will probably generalize better.
我们可以看到中间这个模型可能更好地泛化
The model in the middle looks at this point as noise
中间的模型把这个点看做噪音
while the one in the right gets confused by it and tries to feed it too well.
而右侧的模型会因此困惑 试图较好地填充它
Now the model in the middle will probably be
现在中间的模型很有可能是
a neural network with a slightly complex architecture like this one.
具有稍微复杂结构的神经网络 例如这个
The one in the left will probably be an overly simplistic architecture.
左侧的模型可能是过于简单的结构
Here, for example, the entire neural network is
例如整个神经网络只是一个感知器
just one preceptors since the model is linear.
因为模型是线性的
The model in the right is probably
右侧的模型可能是
a highly complex neural network with more layers and weights than we need.
具有多层和多个权重的高级复杂神经网络
Now here's the bad news.
现在有个很糟糕的消息
It's really hard to find the right architecture for a neural network.
实际上很难为一个神经网络找到正确的结构
We're always going to end either with
我们经常会最终要么出现
an overly simplistic architecture like the one in
左侧过于简单的结构
the left or an overly complicated one like the one in the right.
要么是右侧过于复杂的结构
Now the question is, what do we do?
问题是我们应该怎么办？
Well, this is like trying to fit in a pair of pants.
这像是试图试穿一条裤子
If we can't find our size,
如果我们找不到尺寸
do we go for bigger pants or smaller pants?
我们要不要尝试更大或更小的裤子呢？
Well, it seems like it's less bad to go for
实际上选择
a slightly bigger pants and then try to get
稍大一点的裤子
a belt or something that will make them fit better,
然后选一条腰带之类的东西 可以更适合 这也是不错的方法
and that's what we're going to do.
这就是我们要做的
We'll err on the side of
我们可能会在
an overly complicated models and then we'll
过于复杂模型的一侧犯错
apply certain techniques to prevent overfitting on it.
然后我们运用特定技巧 避免过拟合